<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Think</title>
    <description>Just another minimalist Jekyll theme for technical writing.</description>
    <link>http://alexmorley.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://alexmorley.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 18:11:42 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 18:11:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top Ten Science Blogs/Bloggers of 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-most-prestigious-list-of-blogs-that-i-tuned-into-last-year-and-will-continue-to-watch-closely-for-2017&quot;&gt;The most prestigious list of blogs that I tuned into last year, and will continue to watch closely for 2017.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;im-going-to-be-adding-to-this-list-over-the-next-few-days-so-please-let-me-know-if-youve-got-any-suggestions&quot;&gt;(I’m going to be adding to this list over the next few days so please let me know if you’ve got any suggestions!)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link is-touched&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike&quot; title=&quot;The Spike&quot; aria-label=&quot;The Spike&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;collectionHeader-logoImage js-collectionHeaderLogoImage&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/350/1*SXgKbsryKflVpOZrHXY3Eg@2x.png&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*SXgKbsryKflVpOZrHXY3Eg@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Spike&quot; data-width=&quot;1731&quot; data-height=&quot;455&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Englighted opinions on both neuroscience &amp;amp; acedemia, Mark Humphries’ blog does a great job of explaining complex topics ranging from why we need to move away from thinking about single neurons to the processes underlying decision making. Great for both scientists and other folk alike; if you need some stimulating lunchtime conversation starters, look no further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bishopblog&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://deevybee.blogspot.co.uk&quot;&gt;BishopBlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of many blogs written by proffessor of developmental neuropsychology Dorothy Bishop this one contains “ramblings on acedemic-related matters”. I first started reading Dorothy’s blog as I began to take a serious interest in the publishing and reproducibility crisis that science is currently facing. More interesting for those outside the scientific community might be her regular posts delving into general biological stuff such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://deevybee.blogspot.co.uk/2011/05/x-and-y-of-sex-differences.html&quot;&gt;x and y of sex differences&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://deevybee.blogspot.co.uk/2017/01/a-common-misunderstanding-of-natural.html&quot;&gt;a common misunderstanding of natural selection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ivory.idyll.org/blog&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexmorley/alexmorley.github.io/master/images/ctitusbrownblogtitle.png&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
For those self-proclaimed nerds amongst you C. Titus Brown’s blog is a true gem. Currently he is running a mini-series entitled &lt;a href=&quot;http://caltech.stacksdiscovery.org/scientific-paper-future&quot;&gt;Envisioning the Scientific Paper of the Future&lt;/a&gt; which has been super interesting so far. If you’re looking to get into blogging then check out this slightly tongue and cheek article written at the beginning of this year &lt;a href=&quot;http://ivory.idyll.org/blog/2017-top-ten-reasons-blog-posts.html&quot;&gt;The top 10 reasons why blog posts are better than scientific papers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bjoern.brembs.net&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bjoern.brembs.net/wp/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bloglogo_transparent.png&quot; style=&quot;width:1731;height:455;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bjoern is a professor of neurogenetics at the Universität Regensburg and writes a great blog about both insect behaviour (&lt;a href=&quot;http://bjoern.brembs.net/2016/12/why-did-the-moth-fly-into-the-flame/&quot;&gt;Why Did The Moth Fly Into The Flame?&lt;/a&gt;) as well as some obligatory progressive articles about the state of science and publishing (&lt;a href=&quot;http://bjoern.brembs.net/2016/02/sci-hub-as-necessary-effective-civil-disobedience/&quot;&gt;Sci-Hub As Necessary, Effective Civil Disobedience&lt;/a&gt;). This one is probably more for those already involved in acedemia in some form or another, but nonetheless a great way to while away an hour or two while waiting for your immuno/code/mouse/PI to finish running.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexmorley.me/2017/SciBloggers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexmorley.me/2017/SciBloggers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Con Cambridge - 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I visited Cambridge for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opencon2016.org&quot;&gt;Open Con 2016&lt;/a&gt; satellite event. I went not only because it had some awesome speakers like Erin Mckiernan, but also because I somehow seemed to have missed a similar event in Oxford the week before (whoops…). What is Open Con? Well in the organisers’ words, Open Con is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a platform for the next generation to learn about Open Access, Open Education, and Open Data, develop critical skills, and catalyze action toward a more open system for sharing the world’s information—from scholarly and scientific research, to educational materials, to digital research data…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite a tall brief for a one-day satellite event to fill, but I have come away properly invigorated to work on some projects I have had on the backburner and have fostered some potential new collaborations with some of the awesome folk at Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;erin-mckiernan---how-open-science-helps-researchers-succeed&quot;&gt;Erin McKiernan - How open science helps researchers succeed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was kicked off rather spectacularly by Erin who walked us through &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/HszKqeQ0ZP&quot;&gt;her paper&lt;/a&gt; (without slides!) that was in eLife earlier this year. I’ve read the paper a few times now but still learnt a lot from her presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erin’s main message is that Open Science is there to &lt;em&gt;help&lt;/em&gt; researchers succeed - not to hinder them. In an ideal world it should not be a sacrifice to be open at all, but Erin argues there are already lots of advantages and very few drawbacks to open science. Our challenge is to move towards a community in which a) open is the default and b) researchers know that they will be rewarded for being open. Things are moving in this direction already, and lots of the scare stories about open researchers not getting jobs or getting scooped are probably not representative of reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Five selfish reasons to work reproducibly &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/tYm1vHl23j&quot;&gt;https://t.co/tYm1vHl23j&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OpenConCam?src=hash&quot;&gt;#OpenConCam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; R⓪ss Mounce (@rmounce) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rmounce/status/801740992789495808&quot;&gt;24 November 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t read her paper, then read it:, it is better than anything I am going to write here. One of many highlights of the paper is this striking first figure: &lt;em&gt;Open Access Papers get more citations&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Figure 1 of the paper should be here...&quot; src=&quot;https://elife-publishing-cdn.s3.amazonaws.com/16800/elife-16800-fig1-v2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you wondering whether your journal is going to let you do this, or whether your funding agency will pay for this you can check their policies at two awesome websites I hadn’t heard of before called Sherpa &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sherpa.ac.uk/romeo/index.php&quot;&gt;Romeo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sherpa.ac.uk/juliet/index.php&quot;&gt;Juliet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We need to talk about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ImpactFactor?src=hash&quot;&gt;#ImpactFactor&lt;/a&gt; (even though we know it&amp;#39;s incredibly flawed!!) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emckiernan13&quot;&gt;@emckiernan13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OpenConCam?src=hash&quot;&gt;#OpenConCam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kirstie Whitaker (@kirstie_j) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kirstie_j/status/801731984171134976&quot;&gt;24 November 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erin also told us that for now we still need to talk about impact factor, even if we know it’s flawed -which it is, and you should sign the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ascb.org/dora&quot;&gt;SF Dora commitment&lt;/a&gt; if you agree. While we still need to keep pushing for progress, meeting people/institutions closer to where they are now can make a big difference in terms of impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;laura-james-mainstreaming-open&quot;&gt;Laura James, Mainstreaming Open&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t let the good be the enemy of the perfect” is a sentiment that came through from Erin’s talk but was really brought home by Laura James who was previously CEO of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://okfn.org&quot;&gt;Open Knowledge Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. This idea is something I have always mixed feelings about. It is clearly a broad concept and it is something I often tangle with when thinking about politics politics as well as science politics. Young folk are often charged with being too idealistic, but it is often the case that if you want to see a small change you need to aim for a much bigger one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who has been swept up in Open ideals recently it was probably good for me to be reminded that Open is ultimately a means to an end. For Laura, it should not be a hard &amp;amp; fast principle for how to undertake any project but should instead be used wherever it will make things better. It is still hard for me to think of many places in science that would not benefit from being more open, but I will remember to keep &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I want these areas to be more open in mind: what is the end goal and how will Open make that more achievable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Open is &amp;quot;under the hood&amp;quot;, don&amp;#39;t talk about it explicitly but it has huge effect on humanitarian impact we can achieve. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LaurieJ&quot;&gt;@LaurieJ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/openconcam?src=hash&quot;&gt;#openconcam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Erin McKiernⓐn (@emckiernan13) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emckiernan13/status/801761764786446336&quot;&gt;24 November 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura gave what seemed to me like two very different perspectives on Open Source while describing her work with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fieldready.org/&quot;&gt;Field Ready&lt;/a&gt;, a humanitarian project that uses 3D printing to make supplies in the field. Both seem equally valid and had me thinking for much of my 2 hour journey back to Oxford. Most people would agree that one of the aims of Open is to “empower the many rather than the few”. However we have to also consider that being in a position to use Open Source - i.e. being in a position to release your work for free - is a position of privilege. My take home is that we should be careful before imposing this condition on to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Interesting points about people from privileged positions being able to release designs for free &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OpenConCam?src=hash&quot;&gt;#OpenConCam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Georgina Cronin (@senorcthulhu) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/senorcthulhu/status/801760742135439360&quot;&gt;24 November 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;foucus-group---is-outreach-necessary-for-true-open-access-research&quot;&gt;Foucus group - Is outreach necessary for true Open Access research?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the afternoon session we got into groups and each discussed a single topic related to Open Access. I chose one entitled &lt;em&gt;“Making a paper OA is not necessarily sharing it -perhaps we should be writing in a more understandable way”&lt;/em&gt;. When I read the first part of the questions I thought: “sure, making OA isn’t even close to sharing it. You also need to share the results, data and steps in between (usually code)”. I have thought for some time that publicly funded work should be publicly accessible. But what the author of this question was hitting on is that &lt;em&gt;publicly accessible&lt;/em&gt; also means that we have to communicate what our work means clearly to the public. For sure, not everyone will be able to understand the article itself. And beyond all of the other great reasons for outreach, shouldn’t we have to justify to people why we are spending their &lt;em&gt;taxes&lt;/em&gt; on our research anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the afternoon session we got into groups and each discussed a single topic related to Open Access. I chose one entitled &lt;em&gt;“Making a paper OA is not necessarily sharing it -perhaps we should be writing in a more understandable way”&lt;/em&gt;. When I read the first part of the questions I thought, sure making OA isn’t even close to sharing it, you also need to share the results, data and steps in between (usually code). I have thought for some time that publicly-funded work should be publicly accessible. But, what the author of this question was hitting on, is that &lt;em&gt;publicly accessible&lt;/em&gt; also means that we have to communicate what our work means. For sure, not everyone will be able to understand the article itself. And beyond all of the other great reasons for outreach shouldn’t we have to justify to people why we are spending &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; taxes on our research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is of course worth mentioning that with the ever-increasing pile of things scientists are expected to do it is important that funders/institutions provide sufficient support – and that researchers take advantage of this. This could be in the form of training, journalists, data-management experts etc. In a lot of cases this type of infrastructure is already in place, but many scientists do not know about it. So scientists, ask your librarian/funders for help! And librarians/funders, keep telling us what you have got!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all I’ve got to say about OpenConCam 2016 for now. If want to find out more you can visit their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opencon2016.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; or you can catch up on all of the tweets at this &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/CamOpenAccess/openconcam-2016&quot;&gt;storify&lt;/a&gt;. Oh and one final thing - the Wellcome trusts will be accepting pre-prints on grant applications soon … wooo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wellcometrust&quot;&gt;@wellcometrust&lt;/a&gt; grant applications will accept &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/preprint?src=hash&quot;&gt;#preprint&lt;/a&gt; citations for grant applications from next year &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/openscience?src=hash&quot;&gt;#openscience&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/openaccess?src=hash&quot;&gt;#openaccess&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OpenConCam?src=hash&quot;&gt;#OpenConCam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alexander Morley (@alex__morley) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alex__morley/status/801815140081500160&quot;&gt;24 November 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexmorley.me/2016/OpenConCam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexmorley.me/2016/OpenConCam/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MRC CBU Open Science Day 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I wrote some notes about cool things I learnt at the Open Science day at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrc-cbu.cam.ac.uk/openscience2016&quot;&gt;MRC CBU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reproducibility-preprints-and-why-you-shouldnt-drive&quot;&gt;Reproducibility, PrePrints, and why you shouldn’t drive…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After deciding using my car would make sure I arrived on time I awoke to a flat battery and so had to get the train -on the lovely new Chiltern trains- and so managed to miss the first session on reproducibility- by Dorothy Bishop, and only managed to catch the end of a discussion about preprints and open evaluation - by Lauren Cadwaller and Niko Kriegesorte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was consoled by the fact that when I arrived I knew it was going to be a good crowd as all of the laptop/phone screens I could see contained either terminals or twitter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key slide I did get to see from Niko’s talk was this one:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexmorley/alexmorley.github.io/master/images/Screenshot%20from%202016-11-25%2015%3A37%3A46.png&quot; alt=&quot;Broken link: go look at the slides yourself!&quot; title=&quot;Hover text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(By the way - all of the slides for the talks are up on the MRC CBU’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrc-cbu.cam.ac.uk/openscience2016/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; so you can check out (+find references etc.) any of the talks I do discuss there.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong I agree with him 100%, and I reckon most of the other people did in the room to, but, whether or not you are talking to the converted, it might have been even more useful to at try and think of all of the possible arguments that people might levy against preprints. Not least because then a) we will be better armed when confronted with these questions in the future and b) because if you say to a group of scientists that there are no disadvantages of something you are just inviting them to disagree with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-data-at-the-cbu---rik-henson&quot;&gt;Open Data at the CBU - Rik Henson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coffee Rik gave a great overview of what the CBU is doing in terms of Open Data, and where it plansto go over the next couple of years. They recently had their policies audited by the MRC and given that we (at the MRC BNDU in Oxford) are writing up new Data Management plans at the moment, I thought that we might be able to learn a lot from what the CBU are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rik told us that last year they set up an Open Science commitee and that so far they have implemented a CBU data repository as well as updating their consent forms to allow for data-sharing. If you’re interested in the latter I advise you to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://open-brain-consent.readthedocs.io/en/latest/ultimate.html&quot;&gt;Ultimate Consent Form&lt;/a&gt;. In terms of their data repository, I think they hit on one really important thing that I had only vaguely though about before. Their idea was to have levels of access for different datasets so that for e.g. a dataset could be freely downloadable with just a click; or you might have to fill a very short form with an insitituional email address (which would allow better tracking of data-re-use); or for bigger, more valuable datasets, you would have to fill out a detailed form, which a panel would review, asking for specific parts of a dataset and explaining what you will do with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final option was chosen for a large project known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cam-can.org/index.php?content=dataset&quot;&gt;Cam-CAN&lt;/a&gt;, and over 90 requests were received within a week, which highlights both how useful these datasets could be, but also that managing detailed requests forms can be a lot of work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexmorley/alexmorley.github.io/master/images/Rik_Henson_Retro_Consent.png&quot; alt=&quot;Broken Link&quot; title=&quot;Retrospective Consent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another cool thing, which many people might not realise, is that making human data available retrospectively might be easier than you think -obviously you still need to be sure of this before you do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rik talked about a lot of cool stuff that I haven’t mentioned (like MRC CBU “Technical Reports”, Pre-Registration &amp;amp; Code-sharing), and there are loads of good resources on his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrc-cbu.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Henson_CBUOpenScience_November2016.pdf&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; so check them out if you want to know more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… Coming soon …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-the-other-talks-&quot;&gt;All the other talks …&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok I’m now super tired and I’ve still got to write about the OpenConCam event that happened on Thursday so I’ll just briefly mention what the other brilliant speakers were chatting about!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tibor-auer--camille-maumet---brain-imaging-data-structure---bids--nidm-results&quot;&gt;Tibor Auer &amp;amp; Camille Maumet - Brain Imaging Data Structure - BIDS &amp;amp; NIDM-Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tibor and Camille both gave super fascinating talks about standard formats for sharing in neuro-imaging. They are both part of the INCF community which has brought scientists together from across the globe to collaberate and create standard solutions to the diversity of tools that are used in this field. Not being an imager myself I won’t go on about the details but I really do appreciate that, whatever your field is it is important to try and seek out best practice for storing your data. It can be tempting to re-invent the wheel and create something fancy yourself, but it will only make yours, and others, lives harder in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camille also touched on something that hit a chord with me. For now, even if your field is some way off having a gold standard for sharing your raw data, then it is still possible to take the smaller, but equally important, step of sharing your results. Even just a tabular file with all of your data points is so much richer than giving means and/or p-values. It made me cringe the other day to hear that some people doing large-scale meta-analysis have had to build tools to read the points from the graphs in a pdf document!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;marta-teperek---making-research-data-the-new-water&quot;&gt;Marta Teperek - Making Research Data the New Water&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/alexmorley.github.io/blob/master/images/Marta_T_Data_Like_Water.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Ooops, no image for you, link to the slides above&quot; title=&quot;Research Data Like Water&quot; /&gt;
In this slide Marta described what an ideal research data cycle might look like. We could spend a FAIR bit of time discussing any of these but I’d just like to mention the “recognition and reward” aspect. The fact remains that we have been saying for a super long time that people should be recognised more for their data and while a little progress has been made, it might still be a little while before grant panels etc. really get their head around this. For me there are two important things to consider: the first is make sure that your data &lt;em&gt;is citable&lt;/em&gt; because if it’s not, then you are unlikely to get the credit that you want. The other is that, in my opinion at least, you should be, in most situations, obliged to share your data if you are publicly-funded (i.e. most of us). And even if you aren’t I’m not sure why you should expect the rest of the scientific community to beleive your results if you can’t show your working… which brings me nicely onto…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kirstie-whitaker---showing-your-working&quot;&gt;Kirstie Whitaker - Showing your working&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/alexmorley.github.io/blob/master/images/Kirstie_W_Repro_Repl_Rob_Gen.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Ooops, no image for you, link to the slides above&quot; title=&quot;Is this research ... ?&quot; /&gt;
This was one of my contenders for slide of the day. It’s very easy to get lost in these terms but this little table is so great! Also, a little soberingly, for any piece of research to be really useful it has to be generaliseable i.e. someone else can produce qualitatively similar results with a new dataset and using different software; at the moment however a lot of research isn’t even reproducible using the same code, and the same data - which to me is a pretty low bar! See e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0038234&quot;&gt;this study&lt;/a&gt; where changing the operating system (same software version and data) changed brain volume estimates by ~5% …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chris-chamber-pre-registration-and-registered-reports&quot;&gt;Chris Chamber Pre-Registration and Registered Reports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/alexmorley.github.io/blob/master/images/C_Chambers_The_Problem.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Ooops, no image for you, link to the slides above&quot; title=&quot;The Problem&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chis told us that one of the solutions to many of these problems is pre-registering your studies. He has started a journal format called &lt;a href=&quot;https://cos.io/rr&quot;&gt;Registered Reports&lt;/a&gt; which work like this: you write you introduction and methods, then submit them for review, the study may then be altered somewhat and, if the methodology is good enough, it will be provisionally accepted. You then go and do the experiments and write up your paper which is guaranteed to be accepted if you have done what you said you were going to. This avoids most forms of publication bias, p-hacking and underpowered studies (which would be rejected at stage 1). It also avoids people spending years doing a study which then, if you have null/controversial results, never gets published. I’d not done much reading on this format before, but suffice to say that Chris persuaded me that it’s a great idea and can sit comfortably next to exploratory research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/alexmorley.github.io/blob/master/images/C_Chambers_Reg_Reports.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Ooops, no image for you, link to the slides above&quot; title=&quot;Registered Reports&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elizabeth-byrne---my-experience-of-pre-registering-during-my-phd&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Byrne - My Experience of Pre-Registering during my PhD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think the whole pre-registration thing sounds over the top, or are you an early career researcher who doesn’t think it’s an option for you at this stage? Then check out Elizabeth’s talk &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrc-cbu.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Byrne_CBUOpenScience_November2016.pdf&quot;&gt;slides here&lt;/a&gt; in which she told us about her experience of pre-registering her study as a PhD student. I think another really important benefit that Elizabeth highlighted is that even when you think you have finished designing your study, pre-registration forces you to think about lots of important details that you might have overlooked before; she found that thinking about how many comparisons she would have to correct for at the end made her choose a much simpler study design that was truly focussed on the question she wanted to answer. Her main tip for other researchers at her stage who might be considering this: “Do it!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all it was a truly inspiring day. The CBU, and Cambridge in general, are really leading the way on Open Science and Data Sharing which and I can’t wait to bring all these great examples back to Oxford to see if we can try and catch up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexmorley.me/2016/MRC-CBU-Open-Science-Day/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexmorley.me/2016/MRC-CBU-Open-Science-Day/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breaking Changes - We can't afford the costs of not paying for Open Science</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;breaking-changes&quot;&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-change-in-one-part-of-a-software-system-that-causes-other-parts-to-fail&quot;&gt;“A change in one part of a software system that causes other parts to fail”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever we work on any project, software or otherwise, we always want to make improvements. In the software world these updates can be somewhat neatly divided into two catagories. Some improvements such as a bug-fix or an added feature might fit perfectly within the existing platform, and we might improve the end-user’s experience without any hassle -or without them even noticing. Deciding to make these kinds of changes is easy, and we do it all the time. Sometimes however you hit a point where you realise that a particular feature you would like to see is going to require some major upheaval. Everything that has been built so far assuming -and relying upon- X and you would like to change that to Y. So now we have to think about not only whether this change is an improvement, but also whether the benefits outweigh the cost of making that change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t guessed it by now I am pretty convinced that we have got to the stage in science where we need to make some of these breaking changes. We can try and encourage people to share their data, but if there is no incentive in the current system to do so it won’t be done to a re-useable standard, or at all. We can talk about ignoring impact factors and big journals but if we keep thinking that the end goal of a piece of science is a pdf document then we are still missing the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crux of the matter being, before we point out where Open Science might break the current system, we need to remember it is already broken, and we might have to break it some more in order to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/1172/&quot;&gt;obligatory xkcd comic highlighting point of blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexmorley.me/2016/Breaking-Changes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexmorley.me/2016/Breaking-Changes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
