<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Morley</title>
    <description>Alex Morley</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 17:47:47 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 17:47:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Science for Experimental Design - loopy stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s not a new concept. But when people talk to me about improving the scientific process it really resonates with me when they talk about feedback loops. This framework is broad enough to encompass most ways in which we can think about improving science, but also makes explicit what actions need to be taken, and where bottlenecks are likely to arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
var visible = 1;
function swap() {
  let turn_off = document.getElementById(&quot;img&quot;+visible);
  visible = visible &gt;= 3 ? 1 : visible + 1;
  
  let turn_on  = document.getElementById(&quot;img&quot;+visible);
  turn_off.style.display = &quot;none&quot;;
  turn_on.style.display = &quot;&quot;;
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h4 style=&quot;float:left; margin-top:5px&quot;&gt;Examples of feedback looks in the scientific process.&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;swap()&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;img1&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/C_Chambers_The_Problem.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pre-reg feedback by Chris Chambers&quot; style=&quot;width:60%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pre-registration prevents hacking of the scientific feedback loop - Chris Chambers. Find out more &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/8mpji/wiki/home/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;img2&quot; style=&quot;display:none&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Marta_T_Data_Like_Water.png&quot; alt=&quot;Data Like Water by Chris Chambers&quot; style=&quot;width:60%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Data Production and Re-Use Loop - Marta Teperek.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;img3&quot; style=&quot;display:none&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://alexmorley.me/ContinuousResearch/img/CCW18.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Continuous Research by me&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Continuous Research aims to shorten the feedback loop, and automate integration of research. Find out more &lt;a href=&quot;https://alexmorley.me/ContinuousResearch/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was super excited when the first thing I saw at the Data Science for Experimental Design workshop, held at the Turing Institue, was Daphne explaining how we were going to cover each part of the cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Dr Daphne Ezer Workshop Agend Slide&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Agenda for the workshop in a loop!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;loop-number-1---optimising-experimental-design&quot;&gt;Loop Number 1 - Optimising Experimental Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two talks of the day discussed optimisation algorithms for experimental design. Here we focus on how we can implement closed loop systems that enable us to run experiments that make optimal uses of the resources available, both in terms of time and cost. We were told how finding solutions to these systems can be hugely computationally expensive, and discussed some potential avenues to find shortcuts that are just as good. It’s worth noting that this type of work involves collaborating with statistians and data scientists in the &lt;em&gt;planning&lt;/em&gt; stage of an experiment. All too often we reach out for advice try to solve our inference problems after the data is collected, by which time it may already be too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;loop-number-2---automating-the-discovery-loop&quot;&gt;Loop Number 2 - Automating the discovery loop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://singularityhub.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/adam-robot-scientist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Adam, the first ever &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robot_Scientist&quot;&gt;robot scientist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
Then we moved on to the next level of abstraction, how much of the scientific process can we automate. Ross King told us about Adam, a machine he claims is the first ever robot scientist. In Richard’s view, one of the key steps to sharing science in a reliable way is to use formal, logical languages, rather than natural ones like english or mandarin. By programming a machine using these languages, Richard’s team could extract all the steps from a high-level goal, e.g. “What does this yeast gene do?”, down each layer of abstraction to the observations made on the sensors of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last session before lunch, Dr Vishal Sanchania from Synthace, described Antha, a software platform that has a somewhat smaller remit that Richards robot scientists, but works out of the box with a wide range of hardware, and an thoughtful user-interface. This level of abstraction seems appealing, but many members of the audience were concerned about the lack of clarity in the availability of the source code, or whether there would be an open API that would freely allow third party customisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;loop-number-3---sharing-evaluating-and-re-using&quot;&gt;Loop Number 3 - Sharing, Evaluating, and Re-Using&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the break we had the reproducibility crew and Dr Rachael Ainsworth and Dr Sebastien Besson. Dr Besson spoke about his lab’s project &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Image Data Resource&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Omero&lt;/a&gt;. One of the key points in the scientific feedback loop is other researchers being able to explore the data that lead the original authors to make the concolusiont that they did. These databases allow anyone to explore all different types of image data and metadata in their web based browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Ainsworth then took us on a whirlwind tour of open science. From why you should do it, why your worst collaborator is yourself in 6 months time (hint: your past self doesn’t reply to emails), and some great re-mix and re-use of materials from colleagues open science talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;structural-and-cultural-barriers-to-implementing-optimal-feedback-loops&quot;&gt;Structural and Cultural Barriers to Implementing Optimal Feedback Loops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To close off the day we had three scientists with sociological backgrounds lead discussion groups about cultural and contextual considerations for moving forwards with Data Science for Experimental Design. For me two themes resonated loud and often in these sessions, in terms of what we as scientists should be doing to be effective, 1) we need to actively engage those with expertise in driving institutional change to help us in our efforts 2) we need to make sure we consider the effects of the changes we seek to drive in as many different contexts as possible. The latter point is especially important, what works to increase accessibility to science in one context may not work in another, and without taking these considerations into account we risk not only being ineffective but actively contributing to existing societal inequalities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/data-science-for-experimental-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/data-science-for-experimental-design/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1-pre-review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month or so a group of us in my unit sit down together and discuss a research paper in as much detail as we can for an hour and half. Usually everyone reads it beforehand, but one or two people will present their thoughts on it first before we deep dive into the details. I’d argue that 10 neuroscientists sitting together chatting about a paper is probably the most intense peer review can get. We often find hidden gems, improvements that would make the paper better, and always end up with a bunch of questions to ask the authors. These meetings are usually referred to as “journal clubs” and have been taking place all over the world for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What usually happens with all this feedback though? Nothing. Even we often forget about the issues we discussed. And unless one of us knows the authors personally the feedback very rarely reaches them. Even if it did, there’s little the authors can do to make improvements on an already published paper, short of issuing a corrigendum*, which isn’t something people tend to like doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a great situation. So from now on we are choosing where we can to discuss pre-prints* in our journal clubs. Pre-prints are research papers posted online &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; they undergo traditionall peer-review in a journal, and so they are at a stage where changes can often still be made. We may thus choose to email our comments/questions to the authors so they can consider them, but this isn’t an entirely transparent way of doing things, and the authors might not be the only people who would benefit from reading the comments, nor the only people capable of replying to them. So we’d like to find an open forum for sharing our feedback. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;link&quot;&gt;PRE-Review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRE-Review is a #### run by three scientsts #####. They provide a group on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;authorea&lt;/a&gt; for sharing reviews, as well as guidlines for writing them and formats for organising journal clubs that focus on reviewing pre-prints. What they do is already cool, but they have their sights on building their own platform for pre-print reviews, based on ######. This will allow #####.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Importantly, one of the things that attracts me to PRE-review over some &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;other open forums for sharing reviews&lt;/a&gt; is their explicit aim to provide constructive feedback for the authors and the community, rather than just trying to tear it down. This, I think, as well as their focus on journal clubs, is unique, and puts the projects in good stead to make the biggest, hardest, changes in scientific practice, which surround the cultures of competition and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/1-pre-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/1-pre-review/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>open-web-blog-series</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I loving hearing about what projects other software developers, data scientists, and science scientists are building to make their sphere of the web a better, cooler or weirder place. For the last couple of years I’ve spend most mornings diving into all of my feeds searching for cool stuff before I even get out of bed. Unfortunately, I’m usually cut short by having to go and do my real job, i.e. actually doing research. But this year as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.mozilla.org/fellowships/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Open Science Fellow&lt;/a&gt; I’m going to be able to set some time to really dive into some of these projects and report back what I’ve found 🎉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still trying to work out the best way to do this but planning on having two sections. A couple paragraphs aimed at trying to convince anyone, tech-savvy or not, why the project is exciting. And then the rest will be a deep dive into some of the details that I find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/open-web-blog-series/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/open-web-blog-series/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Applications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most applications to most things get rejected, but we’d all rather focus on the times when things went better. By releasing my applications to jobs/grants etc. I am aiming to normalize failing for myself, keep my head on straight, and maybe there will even be some things in there that are useful for other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/applications&quot;&gt;My Applications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise stated all applications are &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&quot;&gt;CC-BY-4.0&lt;/a&gt;. If you need to do something that doesn’t allow then just get in touch :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/open-applications/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/open-applications/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Decentralised Git Repositry Sharing and Discovery</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Decentralised Git Repo Sharing/Storage backed by Dat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So. Github have &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2018/06/04/microsoft-github-empowering-developers/&quot;&gt;gone rogue&lt;/a&gt;. Ok, not quite, and the way I see it, it was either they got bought-out or shut-down, and I’m glad it was the former. Whatever your feelings on the above may be, it’d be nice to have a full &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;open&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;decentralised&lt;/strong&gt; place to collaborate on software, and other projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before we decide to build it it’d be good to know what’s out there! In terms of (fully) Open Source Git Repository Browsers there’s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/gitiles&quot;&gt;Gitiles&lt;/a&gt; a super minimal browser written in Go.
and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/git/git.git/tree/gitweb&quot;&gt;GitWeb&lt;/a&gt; which is decentralised using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dominictarr/scuttlebutt&quot;&gt;scuttlebut&lt;/a&gt; protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While GitWeb looks really cool, scuttlebutt isn’t a super mature project, and wasn’t greated with file storage in mind, so while it’s great for the repo-browsing interface, it’s not as well suited to hosting the git repositories themselves. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://datproject.org/&quot;&gt;Dat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first thought of using Dat for sharing git repo’s I tried to hack something together. I very quickly realised a) it was a bit more complicated than I thought it was going to be and b) there’s no way I was the first person to try and do this. And most importantly c) I was actually trying to do two things at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the dat protocol as peer-to-peer git remote (on the same levele as http(s) and ssh)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create an interface for sharing/discovery of git repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out number &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/code&gt; has already been put together very neatly by @noffle (github and twitter) in a protocol called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/noffle/hypergit&quot;&gt;hypergit&lt;/a&gt;. “But wait I thought you said you wanted to use the dat protocol?”, well yes, Dat is actually a wrapper around hyperdrive which itself will soon be written on top of hyperdb which is what hypergit is built on. Confusing? A little. But what matter is that hypergit is using the same core technologies as day, but for now is much faster when dealing with large numbers (thousands) or files - which is especially important for a git repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/code&gt; is still up for grabs, but first we need to work out exactly what we want from a p2p git repository browser. So let’s make a wishlist! On github! Fork &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/dgit-web&quot;&gt;this page on github&lt;/a&gt; or using &lt;a href=&quot;https://beakerbrowser.com/&quot;&gt;Beaker Browser&lt;/a&gt; and add your name/handle below plus answers to any of the questions if you have any opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/Decentralised-Git-Reposity-Sharing-and-Discovery/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/Decentralised-Git-Reposity-Sharing-and-Discovery/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Continuous Research - Integrating Open Science</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this then maybe I don’t need to convince you that (wherever possible) it would be really great if researchers like me shared their data, their analysis software, and anything else that would allow someone else to verify, and build upon their research. It’s too early to be complacent, but at least as far as I can see, things are moving in the right direction and soon enough I think funders/publishers will mandate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the promise of someone finding your data/code and re-using it to make new discoveries will not hold for everyone. The manpower required even to just reproduce the computational aspect of every experiment is simply too much, even when everything is shared. As such I think we really need to start thinking about how we can best use our new-found access to research outputs, and how we can keep integrating this years science with last years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I think we’ve already faced some of these challenges, and found solutions, just not in science as such. We have the tools to build massive software projects that contain code that from 10 years and 10 minutes ago but still function correctly. One of they key tools that has enabled this is Continuous Integration, the principle that every change to a code-base is immediately tested against a suite in order to ensure that nothing else has been broken and that the new feature is working as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could we apply this to science? Could we build a framework where every time a new dataset is added, or a better algorithm is developed, this will be immediately tested against all previous results to tell us whether “something has broken”, or something new is found. There are some challenges for sure, both technological and cultural, but I beleive it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alexmorley.me/ContinuousResearch/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you can read my whitepaper on how and why we could build a “Continuous Research” platform. It’s a work in progress and I’d really love your thoughts so please comment below or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/ContinuousResearch&quot;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt; or send me an email (alex0morley@gmail.com).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/continuous-research/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/continuous-research/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>every-data-scientist-should-know</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OK so my job title isn’t actually “data scientist”. But by the end of this year it might be, and while a lot of what I do research-wise is pretty much “data science” there are also a fair few aspects that get ignored in acedemia. While trying to keep growing as a software developer I was super happy to come across &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mtdvio/every-programmer-should-know&quot;&gt;every-programmer-should-know&lt;/a&gt; - a github repo that acts as a highly curated list of things that are super useful to know as a programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while trying to fill in a few of the (many) gaps in my data-sci skill stack I decided to create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;s/programmer/data-scientist&lt;/code&gt; version of the list! I’ve started filling it in with a few of my favourite resources but I don’t have enough experience to really fill this out. So if you’ve got an awesome resource that covers something new then add it to the list; or if you’ve found something that you feel is better than what I’ve put there already then replace it! I will try to spend a some time to give every PR a proper look through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway here it is at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/every-data-scientist-should-know&quot;&gt;every-data-scientist-should-know&lt;/a&gt;, let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;PS. By &quot;should-know&quot; I don't really mean &quot;should&quot;. I mean, you can learn whatever you feel like.
I just stole the title from someone else ¯\\\_(ツ)\_/¯
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/every-data-scientist-should-know/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/every-data-scientist-should-know/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Golden Rules For Data (and Code) Management</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If Nature News and Comment are writing about it, it must be the next big thing eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Data management is inevitably going to be an essential skill in the open-science era.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SrjnAW46na&quot;&gt;https://t.co/SrjnAW46na&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nature News &amp;amp; Comment (@NatureNews) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NatureNews/status/974339459381645314?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;15 March 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hot topic or not managing your data properly is super important for scientific/commercial integrity, and most importantly, your own sanity. It’s so important that my department invited their most bestest PhD student to give &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/SSIFellowship/data-talk&quot;&gt;a talk&lt;/a&gt; on it at our last training day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you couldn’t be bothered to flick through all ten slides then here are said Golden Rules, according to yours truly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Touch the Raw Data&lt;/strong&gt; - back it up and keep read-only copy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a plan!&lt;/strong&gt; - Decide where your data is going to be stored, what its called, when/if it needs to be deleted BEFORE you start collecting it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document Everything&lt;/strong&gt; - You know who the worst person at replying to emails is about what the sampling frequency of channel X was. Nope not him, it actually yourself from a year ago. Keep the documentation with the data!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create the data you want to see in the word&lt;/strong&gt; - Imagine someone was about to give you a dataset that you needed to analyse well in order to get that job you’ve been dreaming about. What would you want it to look like? That’s how yours should look.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try not to re-invent the wheel.&lt;/strong&gt; Before you start creating some crazy new schema, storage format or naming protocol - have a quick google, ask your colleagues. Something that’s already being used is likely going to be better in the long run even if you think there’s a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/GoldenRulesForDataManagement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/GoldenRulesForDataManagement/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mind The Gap</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;mind-the-gap---guest-post-at-software-saved&quot;&gt;Mind the gap - Guest post at &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/blog/2018-02-09-bridging-gap-convincing-researchers-different-backgrounds-adopt-good-enough&quot;&gt;Software Saved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Off of the back of a discussion that was part of the interview process &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SoftwareSaved?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@SoftwareSaved&lt;/a&gt; we wrote a blog post! Check it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/3up1eYfGOL&quot;&gt;https://t.co/3up1eYfGOL&lt;/a&gt; ⌨️💻👨‍🔬👩‍🔬 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/NUPM7mzuwI&quot;&gt;https://t.co/NUPM7mzuwI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alexander Morley (@alex__morley) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alex__morley/status/961903586081943553?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;9 February 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the interview process for the Software Sustainability Institute’s Fellowship programme we broke out into discussion groups in order to exchange ideas one hurdles that need to be overcome for better integration and recognition of the software within research. Out of one of these groups we dissected out the issues that come up when software engineers and researchers do work on the same project. We tried to tease out exactly how and why different expectations about the main outcomes, or goals, of the project might lead to difficulty. Importantly, we also had a stab at how these conflicts can be avoided/resolved going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound interesting? Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/blog/2018-02-09-bridging-gap-convincing-researchers-different-backgrounds-adopt-good-enough&quot;&gt;the post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/Mind-The-Gap/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/Mind-The-Gap/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Software Sustainability Fellowship Application - Update!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;update---i-got-it-&quot;&gt;Update - I got it! 🎉&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Pretty psyched for this! Awesome to become an &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SoftwareSaved?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@SoftwareSaved&lt;/a&gt; Fellow with such a wicked group of people. 💻🎉💪 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/mIoFBMiOtC&quot;&gt;https://t.co/mIoFBMiOtC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alexander Morley (@alex__morley) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alex__morley/status/939093232318930946?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;8 December 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/fellows/alexander-morley&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the link to my profile on the SSI page. More info on my plans coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;application-post&quot;&gt;Application Post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en-gb&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;*Phew* &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SoftwareSaved?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@SoftwareSaved&lt;/a&gt; Fellow application submitted with time to spare.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alexander Morley (@alex__morley) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alex__morley/status/917523404483387392?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;9 October 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I submitted my application to the Software Sustainability Institute yesterday! You can see my application &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexmorley.me/SSIFellowship/application/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; - or the full repo on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexmorley/SSIFellowship&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. And you can find out more about why the SSI is awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.software.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/SSI-Fellowship-Update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/SSI-Fellowship-Update/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
